

# About

I'm a Data Scientist with a versatile scientific background, thanks to my studies in physics & blockchain technologies and my experience as a fullstack developer.

In my spare time I teach physics and mathematics to High School students as a freelancer.

A curiosity about me: I was a professional trained cook (also experienced in restaurant reception) as I studied Hospitality in High School.

That allowed me to work abroad while I was teenager, granting me memorables experiences with several people of different cultures.

### Education

O 2024 - in progress...

**BACHELOR IN ECONOMICS** 

Università degli Studi di Roma La Sapienza, Rome, Italy

O 2022 - 2023 同 DATA STRUCTURES & ALGORITHMS SPECIALIZATION

University of California San Diego, US

O 2022 - 2023 👨
DATA SCIENCE
SPECIALIZATION

IBM, New York, United States

**O** 2019 - 2023

**BACHELOR IN PHYSICS** 

Università degli Studi di Milano Bicocca, Milan, Italy

# 🕰 Languages

ITALIAN (C2)
ENGLISH (C1)

SPANISH (B2)

FRENCH (B2)

### Contact



<u>Milan, Italy</u>



+39 3770982047



maurizio.falconi47@gmail.com



/MaurizioFalconi

# Maurizio Falconi

### Data Scientist

I collected lots of working experiences in hospitality field, therefore i chose to cut it off some from my resume, due to my working goal purposes.

If you are interested to check it out my full working experience, skills and certifications you can visit *falker47/gituhub.io/myresume* 

Note: when it appears the icon 👨 next to an activity you can click on it to see the certification. Every underlined text has its relative link.

### **Freelance Activity**

Q January 2023 - present day

#### **Private STEM Teacher**

I'm teaching physics and mathematics to High School students as a freelancer. So far I provided **300+ hours** of lessons to **20+ students**.

You can reach my Teacher Accounts on <u>LeTueLezioni</u> and <u>SuperProf</u> to check my students reviews, or <u>my website</u> that I developed on my own

## **Working Experience**

September 2023 - August 2024

Crédit Agricole | Via La Spezia 138/A, Parma (PR), Italy

#### **CREDIT RISK ANALYST**

As a member of Credit Risk Modeling Team, I've been working on the development of an Early Warning model Artificial Intelligence techniques (**Machine Learning**).

I also contributed to the Data Collection project in order to analyze the financial stress exerted by <u>Fit-for-55</u>, the green-transition EU plan.

February 2023 - January 2024

MasterZ | Corso di Porta Romana 61, 20122 Milan, Italy



#### **BLOCKCHAIN & DIGITAL ASSETS ACADEMY ATTENDEE**

Winner of two scholarships, one for the 5th edition of the training course, and the another one for the BlockChain Project Lead specialization by AIO Blockchain Lab.

The following skills I learned, were put into practice in the development of a <u>final project work</u>, evaluated among the Top 50 of the entire course, and in the top 3 selected by Ernst&Young:

- Blockchain Technologies, Smart Contracts Notarization, Digital Assets (CBDC / crypto)
- DeFi, DApps, Centralized and Decentralized Exchanges
- March 2023 April 2023

Blazar Group | Via Besso 27, 6900 Lugano, Switzerland



Full-time training course (with project work) where I learned and implemented:

- C#, Azure, MSSQL for backend solutions
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, Angular for frontend solutions
- GitHub and Trello for the entire project task management

#### October 2021 - February 2023

MU Fish | Via Galileo Galilei 5, Nova Milanese (MB), Italy

#### **COMMIS de RANG**

Part-time work where I was in charge of:

- Reception of the restaurant customers
- Booking Management
- Waiting service

#### November 2017 - January 2022

Da Vittorio srl | Brusaporto (BG), Italy

### 4th LEVEL CHEF

Job on call in occasion of important events where I was in charge of:

- Execution and Plating of Da Vittorio most famous dishes
- Cooking Line Preparation
- Contact with the Public